<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>airport people</title><link>https://airportpeople.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on airport people</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 21:09:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://airportpeople.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Premise and Purpose</title><link>https://airportpeople.github.io/thought/20200928/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 21:09:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://airportpeople.github.io/thought/20200928/</guid><description>A Start In my attempts at curating a repository of admittedly amateur philosophical essays, I find myself fairly challenged when trying to form a pure foundation of premises and axioms. It seems to me that any philosophy must start with a consistent set of premises or at least an intuitively sound few axioms to work from. Otherwise, the goal must be to engage with or potentially critique the established work of another — at least in as much as something fruitful may come from compounding one&amp;rsquo;s work on that of another.</description></item><item><title>Airport People</title><link>https://airportpeople.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 15:35:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://airportpeople.github.io/about/</guid><description>Who Airport People is the collection of music, philosophy, and code by me, Leon. I compose post-classical minimalist music, think about epistemology, and educate in data ethics.1
I live in a little house in Fountain Square, Indianapolis, IN, with my partner and my dog. Currently, I am working on my second full-length Airport People album, expected to release at the beginning of 2021.
Why Since the beginning of commercial flight, international and domestic airports have been a meeting place for people from all over the world: family, friends, enemies, strangers, co-workers, and colleagues alike.</description></item></channel></rss>