<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>epistemology on airport people</title><link>https://airportpeople.github.io/tags/epistemology/</link><description>Recent content in epistemology on airport people</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 21:07:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://airportpeople.github.io/tags/epistemology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>on hume’s deontological response to scepticism</title><link>https://airportpeople.github.io/thought/20210204/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 21:07:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://airportpeople.github.io/thought/20210204/</guid><description>introduction In Hume’s Deontological Response to Scepticism (HDRS), Hsueh Qu from the National University of Singapore provides a novel interpretation of Hume’s take on the sceptical system of philosophy.1 At the end of Part IV of A Treatise of Human Nature, Book I (THN 1.4), Hume illustrates the Dangerous Dilemma bound to befall anyone deeply considering a sceptical outlook on their world: if we are to remain sceptical of all things, we must be sceptical of (and may condemn) all reasoning, which is devastative, and if we then avoid scepticism altogether, we are reduced to credulity, of which we should only be ashamed — in his words, we have “no choice left but betwixt a false reason and none at all”.</description></item><item><title>premise and purpose</title><link>https://airportpeople.github.io/thought/20200928/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 21:09:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://airportpeople.github.io/thought/20200928/</guid><description>a start In my attempts at curating a repository of admittedly amateur philosophical essays, I find myself fairly challenged when trying to form a pure foundation of premises and axioms. It seems to me that any philosophy must start with a consistent set of premises or at least an intuitively sound few axioms to work from. Otherwise, the goal must be to engage with or potentially critique the established work of another — at least in as much as something fruitful may come from compounding one&amp;rsquo;s work on that of another.</description></item></channel></rss>