<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thought on airport people</title><link>https://airportpeople.github.io/thought/</link><description>Recent content in Thought on airport people</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 17:54:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://airportpeople.github.io/thought/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prometheus and Google</title><link>https://airportpeople.github.io/thought/20201001/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 13:01:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://airportpeople.github.io/thought/20201001/</guid><description>Introduction In creating media based on myths, symbols, and idols, we may lose the value and meaning of the original if recommender systems and search algorithms do not find a harmonic balance between meaning and object. The burden lies on the recommender to recognize the difference between the &amp;ldquo;common&amp;rdquo; media definition and some other potentially more pure definition or connotation. Whether the former is any more appropriate than the latter is also investigated, along with a generalized form of this phenomenon, comparing words as they exist on common search/recommendation engines, and the same words when they connote other (prior or &amp;ldquo;purer&amp;rdquo;) concepts.</description></item><item><title>Premise and Purpose</title><link>https://airportpeople.github.io/thought/20200928/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 21:09:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://airportpeople.github.io/thought/20200928/</guid><description>A Start In my attempts at curating a repository of admittedly amateur philosophical essays, I find myself fairly challenged when trying to form a pure foundation of premises and axioms. It seems to me that any philosophy must start with a consistent set of premises or at least an intuitively sound few axioms to work from. Otherwise, the goal must be to engage with or potentially critique the established work of another — at least in as much as something fruitful may come from compounding one&amp;rsquo;s work on that of another.</description></item></channel></rss>